本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流
更多中日双语字幕，尽在www.kamigami.org 及微博@诸神字幕组
What is it?
"Guest General, Kingdom of Lusitania
Lord Silver Mask
Hermes"
何事だ
You will have to forgive me
for remaining as I am.
このまま失礼する
After raising that fog upon
the Fields of Atropatene,
アトロパテネの大平原に霧を起こして以来
I have yet to regain my full strength, you see.
体力が戻りきっておらんでの
So, what is the matter at hand
that caused you to summon me?
で　わざわざ俺を呼び出した用件はなんだ
Kharlan is dead.
カーラーンが死んだ
It seems he was killed by Arslan's company.
アルスラーン一党に殺られたようじゃ
To become a corpse exposed to the
elements, still disgraced as a traitor...
裏切り者の汚名を被ったまま　野に屍をさらすはめになろうとは
He is to be pitied.
あわれなことよ
I will instruct my disciples
to continue to aid you.
我が弟子たちには　引き続きお主に力を貸すよう言っておく
But do not misread matters
as they are, Lord Silver Mask.
だが見誤るな　銀仮面卿
The sun of Pars does not shine for you alone.
パルスの太陽は　お主一人のためのみには輝かぬ
1% a) gig These aren't my words a) $3573
日听&翻译
小伍
sora
兰樱
校对
小江
mam
ﬁt f? lfath 9.‘ wa‘lexworld QQ’théd‘ Left bands; 5 a-
片源
Rei
时间轴
电池雪糕
压制
久嘉
Coolkid
There's: nothing beyond ,thisgazygggfg; p
The day I realized that,
: o) i‘fal s --> .<>.pped.%look.ing up :atﬁtbgssky a- u
And in the bottomless swamp,
lopk, thecsa's alihottom:
In this town that‘s growing
evéromoreitaintﬁieuen 99w
Even if y_og jy‘s‘t‘t’riedg tpibgqa,t_he‘the air
You'd egzdgupjbrea‘ghing inﬁhgequfstuff, too
AI,way_s Id§ing, Leaving
Stuﬂbthatis, up heacabje
We‘ve lived trying to keep our hands
ine efof (thp smtbingstbytf in athesieehands;
YLQUJ axle; intend, Baby, LQrLeam
if H I'BgfgnelLl knawjtf my. be; at (1' xi» 0
Wasfﬁglljof thingsgl Eaglﬁpdogeéall, the way
Always losing, leaving
Even the ,unbeacablg stuff
Because I don't want to live my days
I amenting, unable to ke_ep thgm sgﬁe :
Y:QUJ ewe.- ﬁrziezad, Baby, zﬂrteam
I'II grtowg'ggepgsgrgnger
’ n :iTh'sesﬁgaa'ea'tmy words
But Our words
Having learned from Kharlan's final
words that King Andragoras still lives,
カーラーンの最期の言葉で　アンドラゴラス王が存命であることを知った
Narsus and Daryun parted ways with Arslan
ナルサスとダリューンは　アルスラーンと別れ
and infiltrated the Royal Capital
in order to locate the King.
その居場所を探るべく　王都に潜入していた
The devastation is considerable.
随分と荒れたな
Yes.
ああ
I would hate for His Highness to see this.
殿下に見せたくはないな
Lady Tahamenay.
タハミーネ殿
Are you as well as ever?
変わりないか　欲しいものはないか
Is there anything you want?
Do not hesitate to tell me.
なんでも言ってくれ　不自由はさせぬゆえ
I would not have you wanting.
l-l bring good tidings today, you see.
きょ…今日はな　よい報告を持ってきたのじゃ
With the dawning of the new year,
年が明ければ　予は王ではなく　皇帝を称することになるだろう
I am likely to style myself,
not as king, but as emperor.
The Emperor of the new Lusitanian Empire.
新ルシタニア帝国の皇帝じゃ
So, the matter at hand
is this, Lady Tahamenay...
そこでじゃのう　タハミーネ殿…
The people believe that an
emperor must have an empress!
皇帝には皇妃が必要と世間は思っておる
I, too, believe this to be correct.
予もそれは正しいと思う
Is there anything you would like?
何か欲しいものはないか
That cursed heathen does not
accept the divine grace of Yaldabaoth!
イアルダボートの恩寵を受けぬ　呪われた異教徒め
なぜ　国王陛下はあやつを火刑にせぬ
Why does His Majesty not burn her at the stake?!
"Archpriest of the Faith of Yaldabaoth
Bodin"
lnnocentis VII, the King of Lusitania,
ルシタニアの王　イノケンティス七世が
was not executing Andragoras, the King of Pars,
パルスの王アンドラゴラスと　その妃タハミーネを処刑しないことに
or Tahamenay, his queen.
業を煮やした大司祭ボダンは
Having lost his patience, Archpriest
Bodin set out to vent his frustration
その腹いせに　パルスの王立図書館に収蔵してあった
by burning twelve million volumes'
worth of rare historical texts
１２００万冊にも及ぶ　貴重な歴史的書物を焼き尽くすべく　行動に出た
that were stored in Pars's Royal Library.
Unleash the fI ames! Burn it all!
火を放て　焼き尽くせ
You can't! This is the treasure of Pars...
ダメだ　パルスの宝を…
Stay back! Stay back!
寄るな　寄るな
Burn them! Burn them!
燃やせ　燃やせ　邪悪な異教徒の書じゃ
They are evil, heathen texts!
Destroy them! Reduce every last volume to ash!
滅せ　残らず　灰に処すのだ
Lord Archpriest...
大司祭様…
Eh?
Heathen texts though they may be,
いかに異教の書とはいえ
こ…これほど貴重な書物を研究もせぬまま
sh-should we be consigning
such valuable texts to the fI ames
without even examining them?
火中に投じてよいものでしょうか
Even if they must be burned, their value...
燃やすとしても　その価値を…
You blasphemer!
冒とく者め　人の世にはイアルダボートの聖典だけで十分だ
The world of man only needs
the holy book of Yaldabaoth.
Texts written at the behest of
the Devil must be destroyed.
悪魔が書かせた書は滅ぼさねばならぬ
But to burn even the medical texts...
ですが　医学書まで燃やすのは…
Silence!
黙れ
Those who wholeheartedly
worship the God of Yaldabaoth
イアルダボート神を心から敬う者には　病魔など取りつかぬ
will not be possessed by disease!
Those who fall ill harbor
seeds of evil in their hearts
病にかかる者は心に悪しき種を宿すゆえ　神の懲罰を受けるのだ
and that is why God punishes them!
Though he may be the ruler of a kingdom,
たとえ　一国の国王であろうとも
should any man be seized with evil intentions,
異教徒の女をめとろうなどと　邪心を起こしたとき
such as taking a heathen woman to wife,
disease shall surely serve as
God's staff to strike down the arrogant!
病毒は神の杖となって　おごれる者を撃つであろう
Those with evil in their hearts, repent!
邪心ある者は悔い改めよ
Taking money and objects of value is one thing,
財貨を奪うというならまだしも　文化を焼き尽くすとはな…
but to burn away our culture...
This goes beyond the action of savages.
もはや　蛮人ともすら言えぬ
--Burn! Burn! Perish!
--They are crude monkeys!
燃えよ　燃えよ　滅せ
猿のやることだ
Let me kill that man named Bodin.
あのボダンとかいう男は　俺に殺させろ
The King and King's brother
and such, I leave to you.
国王だの王弟だのは　お前に任せる
Very well.
よかろう
Mistress Farangis, I am here.
ファランギース殿
ここです
How have things been on the main road?
どうじゃ　街道の様子は
Oh, beyond uneventful...
いや　何もなさすぎて
Ah!
おお　ちょうど腹がすいていたところです
It just so happened that I was hungry.
To think that you would perceive
my thoughts, Mistress Farangis.
俺の思いがフランギース殿に伝わるとは…
Mayhap we truly are
linked by an invisible thread.
やはり　我ら　見えない糸で結ばれておるのやも
It was EI am who prepared that.
用意したのはエラムじゃ
What?
まあよい　夜通しで疲れておろう　代わろう
Well, never mind.
You nmust be tired from being
up all night. I will relieve you.
No, no, that will not be necessary.
いやいや　それには及びませぬ
This is the only road that
leads to the village, after all.
村に至る道はここだけですし　見張るに造作もありませぬ
Standing watch over it is no trouble at all.
Thanks to that, I have had plenty of time
おかげで　ファランギース殿を賛美する詩をじっくり創作できました
to compose a poem that sings
your praises, Mistress Farangis.
Please listen to what...
お聞きくださ…
Oh, oh, oh, where are you going?
ああ　いずこへ
If that is the case, I will ask
you to carry on indefinitely.
そういうことなら　ずっとこのまま頼むとしよう
But then, my sentiments will
end up overrunning this forest.
しかし　それでは　我が思いはこの森に満ちあふれてしまいます
It would be terrible if the
forest were to become poisoned.
森が毒気づいては大変じゃ
Do you suppose Daryun and
Narsus have arrived in Ecbatana?
ダリューンとナルサスはエクバターナに着いたであろうか
Yes.
はい
Determining the whereabouts
of my lord father and lady mot-her
父上と母上の所在を確かめることは大事ではあるが
is certainly important, but...
To ride into the very
center of the Lusitanians...
ルシタニアの巣窟に乗り込むなんて
No matter how capable those two are...
いくら二人の腕が立つといっても…
It does not even bear my saying so,
私が申し上げるまでもなく
but there is no cause for Your Highness
to worry about those two.
お二人なら　殿下のご心配には及びませんよ
That is true, but...
そうだが…
Did you face no danger when
you were in the Royal Capital?
エラムは王都で危険な目に遭わなかったのか
Uh, no. Unlike those two,
my face is not known, so...
あっ　いえ　私はお二人と違い　面が割れておりませんでしたので
Your Highness, I am going to fetch water.
殿下　水をくんでまいります
Then I will come as well.
では　私も行こう
No, please wait inside, Your Highness.
いいえ　殿下は中でお待ちください
On your own, you will be forced
to make the trip many times.
エラム１人では　何度も行くことになるであろう
And besides, it is more
heartening to act as a pair.
それに　２人で行動する方が心強い
You leave me no choice.
しかたありませんね
Please accept this.
どうぞ
Here, I thought we'd
arrived at the Royal Capital
王都に着いたと思ったら…
and now we're turning right back
for the Keep of Saint Emmanuel.
すぐにまた聖マヌエル城へ取って返すとはな
I swear! They say he's a
damn deadly serious commander.
まったく　くそ真面目な隊長らしいぜ
He'll hear you.
聞こえるぜ
Let's at least get some good
rest while we're in this village.
せめてこの村ではゆっくり休ませてもらおうぜ
Come on! Keep bringing more!
ほら　もっと持ってこい
There seems to be no one around.
誰もいないようです　急ぎましょう
Let us hurry.
Thank goodness. It does not
seem to have run dry yet.
よかった　まだ水はかれていないようです
All right.
よし
Your Highness, allow me...
殿下　私が…
Oh, even I am capable of a paltry...
何　これくらい　私にだって
Your Highness...
殿下　大丈夫ですか
Are you all right?
Yes, I am fine.
平気だ
Oh, more importantly...
あっ　それより
I am sorry. It seems I have dropped the pail...
すまない　桶を落としてしまったようだ
It will be fine. I will go and
find a replacement right away.
大丈夫です　すぐに代わりのものを探してまいりましょう
殿下は　あそこで待っていてください
Please wait over there, Your Highness.
I, too, will...
私も…
I need to be of at least some use.
少しは役に立たないとなぁ
Right now, I am nothing but a burden.
今の私は　ただの足手まといだ
Please don't do this!
やめてくれ
If you value your daughter's life,
娘の命が惜しかったら　素直に金めのものをここに持ってこい
don't put up a fight and
bring your valuables here!
No!
いや
I already handed over my property
to the Lusitanian soldiers
財産はすでにルシタニア兵に差し出したし　改宗もした
and I converted as well!
All I have left is my daughter!
私には娘しか残っていない
Don't lie!
うそをつけ
It's the truth!
本当だ
Don't you value your daughter's life?
娘の命が惜しくはないのか
Please don't do this!
やめてくれ
Hurry up.
おらぁ　早くしろ
--Please!
"Or I'll really kill her.
お願いだ
うるせぇ
--I am begging you!
--Come on, hurry up and bring it all here.
頼む
ほら　さっさと持ってこい
Please give my daughter back!
娘を返してくれ
I am begging you!
頼む
Hurry it up!
おい　早くしろ
Stop this!
やめてくれ
やめないか
Who the hell are you?
なんだ　お前
Let her go!
その人を放せ
What? You're coming at us with that thing?
なんだ　そんなもん構えて
You saying you want to fight us?
やるってんのかよ　俺たちと
If you let her go, I will not harm you.
放してくれれば　危害は加えない
What was that? Do you understand
the situation here? Eh?
なんだと　どういう状況か分かってんのか　おい
待て
Wait!
What are you doing?!
何をしている
エ…エトワール様
Commander Étoile!
Can you men defend your current conduct
お前たち　今の行いをイアルダボート神の御前で申し開きできるのか
before the God of Yaldabaoth?!
いや…
Return to your unit!
隊に戻れ
あぁ…
You two go as well.
お前たちも行け
How long are you going
to hold that thing up for?
いつまで　そんなもの構えておる
Y-You! Could it be?
あっ　お前　もしや…
Oh!
You are!
やはり
--That spoiled rich boy!
--The Lusitanian boy soldier?!
あのときの甘ったれ坊ちゃん
ルシタニアの少年兵
お前　よく生きてたなぁ
I'm impressed that you survived.
真っ先に死ぬタイプだと思ってたぞ
I pegged you for the type
to die straight off the bat.
まあ　なんとか
Well, I managed somehow.
腕に自信もないくせに　金持ち一家を助けようとしたのか
You don't even know your way around a fight
and you still tried to help that rich family?
You're as naïve as ever.
相変わらず　お人よしだな
Oh, no...
あっ　いや…
ただ　部下の無礼は謝罪する
But I do apologize for
my men's lack of civility.
Those were your men?
あの者たちは部下なのか
Yes. I'm in charge of a small company.
ああ　小隊を預かっている
Our positions are completely
flipped compared to back then.
あのときとは立場が真逆だな
もう　我々を奴隷にできまい
You can't make us slaves now!
I would not... make you slaves.
奴隷には…しないよ
Even if you wouldn't,
I bet Andragoras and Arslan would!
お前がしなくても　アンドラゴラスやアルスラーンはするだろ
何せ　邪悪な異教徒の大将どもだ
After all, they're the
leaders of the evil heathens!
I heard that those bastards
each have two twisted horns,
あいつら　２本のねじれた角が生えて
口は耳まで裂けて　黒い尻尾が生えていると聞いたぞ
their mouths split ear-to-ear,
and they have black tails!
パルスの愚民どもは悔い改め
The ignorant masses of
Pars will all have to repent
and convert to the Faith of Yaldabaoth.
皆イアルダボート教に改宗しなければならない
もしも私がお主たちの神を信じられなかったら　どうする
If I were not able to find it
in myself to believe in your god,
what would you do?
What? Such a thing would be impossible!
はあ　そんなことは起こりえない
Once you are touched by the Faith of Yaldabaoth,
イアルダボート教に触れれば　その偉大さが分からないはずがない
there is no way you wouldn't
see the gloriousness of it.
The original meaning of "Yaldabaoth"
イアルダボートとは
in Archaic Lusitanian is "sacred ignorance."
もともと古代ルシタニア語で聖なる無知の意味なのだ
Do you know, Daryun?
知ってるか　ダリューン
彼らがパルスに侵攻してきたのは
They apparently invaded Pars
because their holy book says
聖典に　世界で最も美しく豊かな土地は
that the most beautiful and
prosperous land upon the earth
イアルダボート教の信者のものであると　書かれているからだそうだ
belongs to the believers
of the Faith of Yaldabaoth.
How utterly self-serving.
勝手極まる話だな
それで　ルシタニア人どもは　その神の仰せとやらを心から信じているのか
So, this god's so-called bidding...
Do the Lusitanians earnestly believe in it?
さて　信じているのか
Well, whether they believe
or pretend to believe in order
to justify being the aggressor...
信じるふりをして　自分から侵略を正当化しているのか
人は平等というのなら　何故エクバターナに攻め入ったのだ
If it is your assertion that all men are equal,
why did you invade Ecbatana?
What?
何
If you mean to say that Pars's
system of slavery is discrimination,
パルスの奴隷制度を差別というなら
what of Lusitania's conduct towards
the people of the Royal Capital?
王都にいる民へのルシタニアの行いは　なんと説明する
How do you explain that?
何を訳の分からないことを言っている
What nonsense are you spouting?!
Parsians are heathens,
so they can be treated differently!
パルスは異教徒だから　差別していいのだ
Those who do not follow the
teachings of the Faith of Yaldabaoth
イアルダボート教の教えに従わぬ者に　存在意味はない
have no purpose existing!
矛盾していないか
Is that not contradictory?
What?!
なんだと
見つけました　殿…
I found one, Your...
Wait! He is an old friend!
待て　この者は旧知の友人だ
友人
Friend?
友人などではない
I am no friend!
No?
ではない
At any rate, he is not the enemy!
とにかく　敵ではない
いつぞやはお前を人質にして　逃げ延びることができた
At one time, I took you hostage
and that allowed me to escape safely.
I thank you for that.
礼を言っておく
生きていたければ　むちゃは控えろ
If you want to stay alive,
refrain from acting recklessly.
Also, I have one last thing I want to ask you.
それから　最後に一つ聞きたい
Yes? What is it?
ああ　なんだ
Do you know of the Lusitanians
who were with me back then?
あのとき　私と一緒にいたルシタニア人を知らないか
君の仲間は全員殺された…
Your friends...
...were all killed.
I see.
そうか
Read that and study the Faith of Yaldabaoth.
それを読んで　イアルダボート教を学べ
I had braced myself for this,
覚悟はしていたが
but seeing for myself as the Lusitanian army
throws their weight about here,
ここでルシタニア軍がでかい面をしているのをじかに見ると
負けたことを痛感するな
it makes me painfully aware of our defeat.
Now, how do we take back this place?
さて　どうやってここを取り戻す
Let us see...
そうだな　例えば　王子の名で
For example, we could free the slaves
all across Pars in the Prince's name
パルス全土の奴隷を解放し　奴隷制度を全廃すると約束する
and promise to completely abolish slavery.
Even if only one-in-ten take up arms,
そのうち１割が武器を取っても　５０万からの大軍を編制できる
we could form a massive army
of five hundred thousand and up.
But in this case, it would be
imperative that we be self-sufficient.
この場合　自給自足が前提になるがな
なるほど
That makes sense.
ただし　そうなれば
However, if that happens,
we will not be able to expect
the support of slave owners
奴隷を所有する領主や貴族どもの支援は期待できなくなる
such as the vassals and nobles.
And even if we freed the slaves,
not everything would be well and good.
それに　奴隷を解放しても　それで全てよしというわけにはいかぬものさ
What comes after will be the hard part.
そのあとの方が大変でな
It will not go as one might
imagine from behind a desk.
机の前で空想しているようなわけにはいかぬ
痛ぇ
Whoa! Hey! Make way, you dimwit!
おい　道を空けろ　このぼんくら
誰にぶつかってるか分かってんのか
Do you know who you ran into?!
I serve under Erān Kharlan...
俺はエーラーン・カーラーンの部下…
ダ…
Da...
Daryun!
ダリューン
Running away without even fighting you...
戦いもせずに逃げ出すとは　よく己の力量をわきまえているな
He has a good grasp of his own capabilities.
追うか
Do we go after him?
まずは俺一人で行こう
First, I will go alone.
やっぱりナルサスだ
I knew it! It's Narsus.
Because of you bastards,
we've got nowhere to go now!
てめぇらのせいで　俺たちの居場所がねぇんだ
死ぬ前に　アルスラーン王子の居場所を吐いてもらおう
Before you die, you'll tell us
where to find Prince Arslan.
痛ぇ
Did you think that alone,
I would be easy to deal with?
私一人なら　くみしやすいとでも思ったかね
Before you die, how about you tell
us where to find King Andragoras?
死ぬ前に　アンドラゴラスの居場所を吐いてもらおうか
l-l don't know!
し…知らん
I really don't know! It's the truth!
本当に知らんのだ
本当だ　俺も命が惜しい　知っていれば教える
I value my life, too! I'd tell you if I knew!
I do not care if they are merely rumors.
単なるうわさでもかまわん　お前自身のために思い出せ
Recall what you know, for your own sake.
K-King Andragoras is alive.
アンドラゴラス王は生きている
That, we know.
それは知っている
It seems he's being imprisoned somewhere.
どこかに幽閉されているらしい
もともとカーラーン様は　ごくごく側近にしかそれを教えていなかった
Lord Kharlan only told
those closest to him to begin with.
ルシタニアの将軍たちですらそのことを知らないのだ
Even the generals of
Lusitania don't know about it.
What of Queen Tahamenay?
タハミーネ王妃は
ルシタニア王　イノケンテス七世と結婚すると
She's to marry lnnocentis VII,
the King of Lusitania.
ルシタニア兵がうわさしているのを聞いた
I heard some Lusitanian
soldiers gossiping about it.
王のひと目ぼれだったと
They said it was love
at first sight for the King.
王妃様の美貌も罪なことだ
The Lady Queen's beauty is a terrible thing.
しかし　どうする
But what do we do?
たとえ　陛下が生きておいででも
Even assuming that His Majesty is alive,
he may be harmed as an obstacle to the marriage.
結婚の障害になるとして害されるかもしれぬ
あるいは　ルシタニア国王がアンドラゴラス王の命を引き換えに
Or there is the possibility
that the King of Lusitania is
pressing the Queen to marry him
in exchange for King Andragoras's life.
王妃に結婚を迫っているかもしれんな
もう少し情報が欲しいところだ
I would prefer to have
a little more information.
もう一度別れて　釣りをするか
Shall we split up and go fishing again?
ああ
Yes.
What became of Lord Garshasph,
who was guarding this city?
ここを守っていたガルシャースフ殿はどうなっただろう
We do not know the
whereabouts of Lord Sim, either.
サーム殿の行方も分からぬ
How many of His Highness's allies still remain?
殿下の味方は　どれくらい残っているのか
何事か　探っている者がいると聞いてな
I heard that there was a man
snooping around for something.
痴れ者　名を聞いておこうか
Skilled. I am inclined to know your name.
ダリューン
Daryun.
こいつは傑作だ　あのヴァフリーズの甥か
This is hilarious.
The nephew of that Vahriz, eh?
Daryun, I will tell you something.
ダリューン　教えてやろう
貴様の伯父ヴァフリーズを殺ったのは
The one who killed your uncle, Vahriz, is me!
この俺だ
なっ
アンドラゴラスの飼い犬めが　それにふさわしい報いを受けたわ
That damn hound of Andragoras's.
He got what he deserved!
Will you emulate your uncle in death as well?!
貴様の死にざまも伯父に倣うか
Curse you, Daryun!
おのれ　ダリューン
やけど
Burns?
Hey, now, will you not even ask me my name?
おいおい　名前も聞いてくれないのか
I feel embarrassed having
to offer an introduction myself.
こちらから名乗るのは気恥ずかしいではないか
Who are you, you clown?
誰だ　道化者
Then, allow me to formally state...
では　改めて
我が名はナルサス
My name is Narsus.
Under the reign of the next King of Pars,
次のパルス王の世に　宮廷画家を務める身だ
I am to serve as the Court Painter.
The Court Painter, you say?
宮廷画家だと？
As heedless of art as you are,
I doubt you would know,
芸術に無縁なお主は知るまいが　画聖マニの再来と人は呼ぶ
but people call me the second coming
of the Master Painter Mani.
誰が呼ぶか
No one calls you that!
A pet hound and an inept painter.
飼い犬とへぼ画家か　お似合いだな
You make a good match.
Why you!
貴様
ここは一旦退いた方がよさそうだな
It seems best that we
withdraw for the time being.
ああ　そうだな
Yes, agreed.
Damn it! They got away!
くそっ　逃げられた
逃げ足の速いヤツらだ
Those bastards are fast!
I am sure we will meet again.
いずれまた会えるだろうよ
That bastard is frighteningly good.
ヤツめ　恐ろしく腕が立つ
お前が来なければ　危ないところだった
If you had not come,
I would have been in danger.
そんなことはどうでもいい
Such things do not matter!
あいつ　俺をへぼ画家呼ばわりしたんだぞ　気に食わん
That bastard called me an inept painter!
I do not like it!
By the way, that man...
ところで　あの男
Was his mask merely to hide his cause?
仮面は大義を隠すためだけか
それとも　他人に素顔を知られぬためか
Or was it to prevent
others from knowing his face?
I do not know.
分からん　だが
But sooner or later, we are bound
to have to settle things with him.
いずれ　決着をつけねばなるまい
The azure crescent moon
wheels across the night sky
The glittering world transcends the clouds
With this journey's beginning that you dance now
Off into the yonder wishes go, drifting
When a tale that is shapeless
Spreads across the moonlight
The treasure that is within you
Melts away into the wind now
Tomorrow, try to take
wing as your unvarnished self
Sometime, somewhere,
you wanted this, remember?
You can hear it, can't you?
There; that shining dream from that day
The azure crescent moon
wheels across the night sky
The glittering world transcends the clouds
With this journey's beginning that you dance now
Off into the yonder wishes go
Oh, 'til this dream comes to an end
口数の多すぎるカシャーンの城主は
Now that the Prince has
neatly fallen into his clutches,
懐に飛び込んできた王子を自分自身の欲のために
the overly talkative master of
Kashan Fortress likely intends
最大限に利用するつもりであろう
to take full advantage of the
Prince to further his own ambitions.
次回　カシャーン城塞の主
Next time, "The Lord and
Master of Kashan Fortress."
"Chapter X
The Lord and Master of Kashan Fortress"
少年は　そして王となる
And thus, the boy would become king.